Julián Lopez Baasch

{Computer Scientist, Economist}
Av. Libertador 5386, Buenos Aires, Argentina
+54-911-6267-7072
julianlopezba@gmail.com

PRINCIPAL INTERESTS

I am an economist turned computer scientist who loves building machine learning solutions. My research interests lie in the intersection of economics and machine learning. More specifically, I am interested in understanding the human and social dynamics using artificial agents that interact in a game-theoretic setting. Thus, I found in agent-based computational economics and MARL methods a natural fit for my interests.

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

M.Sc. Intelligent Systems

2019

AIML GROUP, Universitat Pompeu Fabra, Barcelona, Spain

- Research in Multi Agent Reinforcement Learning under direction of prof. Martí Sànchez-Fibla.
- Dissertation title: Estimating loss aversion in human behavioral data: A Bayesian approach using Reinforcement Learning.
- Coursework: Machine Learning, Autonomous Systems, Pattern Recognition, Natural Language Interaction, Computer Vision, Web Intelligence, Data Driven Social Network Analysis

M.Sc. Economics 2014

Universidad Torcuato Di Tella, Buenos Aires, Argentina

- Focus areas: Numerical Methods and Game Theory.
- Research in quantitative finance under direction of prof. Nicolás Merener.
- Coursework: Real Analysis, Measure Theory, Dynamic Programming, Evolutionary Game Theory, Causal Inference, Social and Economic Networks, Stochastic Calculus applied to Finance

Licenciate in Economics

2011

Universidad Torcuato Di Tella, Buenos Aires, Argentina

• Minor in Mathematics and Satistics.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Sr. Data Scienitst

2019 - Present

Banco galicia, Buenos Aires, Argentina

- Leading a data science team with the goal of designing, executing, and delivering data products using company data and third-party sources.
- Trained and deployed NLP models for multi-class and multi-label classification
 of comments and posts in social networks (Twitter, Instagram, and Facebook).
 Served this model through a RESTful API for leveraging opinion mining of
 customers on own and third-party channels.
- Web Scraping of main e-commerce platforms in Latin America which generated sales leads on a daily basis.
- Developed and deployed a model for fraudulent users detection in social networks, based on profile picture and description similarity.

Machine Learning Consultant

2019 - Present

As a freelance data scientist, I've assisted to a micro-lending fintech startup with:

- Feature engineering and integration of features into the machine learning pipeline.
- Building an NLP based clustering model of mobile text data points.

Data Analyst

2014 - 2017

DIRECTV Latin America, Buenos Aires, Argentina

- Responsible for implementing analytical solutions to various datadriven problems related to Customer Experience regional office.
- Developed a model for measuring repeated TV content between channels based on Jaccard Index.
- Implemented a predictive model of prepaid recharges based on media, sports and social events.
- Deployed a logistic regression model to predict the level of satisfaction based on the customer journey records.

TEACHING (at Universidad Di Tella)

• Undergrad TA in Law and Economics

Prepared text materials for 'Law and Economics' course, BS in Economics. Helped +30 students gain a better understanding of the practical exercises and theory. Assisted group study in the problem sets solving.

SKILLS

 Machine Learning, Deep Learning, NLP, Computer Vision, Deployment, RESTful API, Web Scraping, Leadership

STACK

• Languages:

Python, Pytorch, TensorFlow, Keras

• Framework:

Flask, Docker, AWS

• Databases:

MySQL, PostgreSQL, Hadoop, Hive, Spark

• Other:

SNAP, Networkx, Matlab, OpenCV, javascript